<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<NewsItem><ARTICLEID>MEXP-UNLIC-18</ARTICLEID><DATELINE>2018-07-09</DATELINE><HEADLINE>Unlicensed Carrier Radios 2018</HEADLINE><SUMMARY>A 5-year forecast of LTE-U and Carrier Wi-Fi, including LAA, MulteFire, CBRS, LWA, and other variations.   Clear technology comparisons and cost analysis illustrate why operators are investing in each technology.</SUMMARY><NEWSLINETEXT>"The use of unlicensed spectrum for carrier and public services has been confined to the Wi-Fi technology through the “carrier unlicensed radio” infrastructure equipment ranging from standalone access point (AP) mounted at outdoor public hotspot locations to customer premise equipment (CPE) at homes and businesses.  Over the past several years, the mobile industry has defined several 3GPP standards-based approaches including Licensed-Assisted Access (LAA) for carrier aggregation, standalone LTE use in unlicensed (MulteFire), and LTE use in shared spectrum in the USA (CBRS) to more efficiently use unlicensed spectrum.  The “LTE-based” carrier unlicensed radio equipment market is forecasted to grow quickly to $1.6B in 2023, growing from 2% of the total carrier unlicensed wireless infrastructure market including Carrier Wi-Fi to almost 17% of the total in 2023.   With the large base of Wi-Fi integrated CPEs shipping in hundreds of millions, the Carrier Wi-Fi infrastructure market will remain stable around $8B.   Conversely, the LTE-based unlicensed and shared spectrum technologies like CBRS and MulteFire will not meaningfully impact the Enterprise WLAN market.  Mobile Experts expects CBRS and MulteFire technologies to open up new market opportunities in “private LTE” and IoT applications.  The LTE-unlicensed use in the Enterprise WLAN market will not be a “zero-sum game.”  We expect the Enterprise WLAN market to grow 36% in 2023 from its 2017 level.&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
With mobile operator preference for LTE-based solution, the standalone AP segment of the carrier unlicensed radio infrastructure market is expected to trend down in the near term.  While the cable operators and other OTT providers like fixed wireless ISPs in rural areas will continue to adopt Wi-Fi as they transition to 802.11ax, the mobile operators will look to LAA in “hotspot” locations to increase network capacity to tout “Gigabit LTE” service.  The shared spectrum use in the 3.5 GHz CBRS band in the USA is expected to bring diverse group of service providers, but the cable operators are expected to be active users of this band for mobile services.  &#13;
&#13;
The unlicensed and shared spectrum segment of the carrier infrastructure market is undergoing a rapid change as new technologies, new spectrum, and heightened competition between cable and mobile operators are incentivizing the different service provider groups to stake a claim.  The introduction of LTE-based technologies such as LAA and MulteFire and novel approaches to open up more spectrum under coordinated sharing like CBRS will increase the overall carrier wireless infrastructure equipment market leveraging unlicensed and shared spectrum.&#13;
"&#13;
</NEWSLINETEXT><BYLINE>Kyung Mun</BYLINE><SOURCE>Mobile Experts Inc.</SOURCE><KEYWORDS>LTE-U LAA LWA LWIP WiFi Carrier WiFi</KEYWORDS><ATTACHMENT>mexp-unlic-18 rev0 ericsson.pdf, mexp-unlic-18 rev0 ericsson.xlsx, </ATTACHMENT></NewsItem>
